This will begin to make things right.
I've traveled too far and seen too much
to ignore the despair in the galaxy.
Without the Jedi, there can be
no balance in the Force.
Well, because of you,
now we have a chance.
The General's been after this
for a long time.
Oh, the General?
To me, she is royalty.
Well, she certainly is that.
We got company.
You have to hide.
You have to leave.
Go.
Come on, BB-8, hurry!
STORMTROOPER'. Blast that X-Wing!
Over there! Over there!
I see them.
You take this.
It's safer with you than it is with me.
You get as far away from here
as you can.
Do you hear me?
I'll come back for you.
Itwill be all right.
Keep moving!
Stay here.
Look how old you've become.
Something far worse
has happened to you.
You know what I've come for.
I know where you come from.
Before you called yourself Kylo Ren.
The map to Skywalker.
We know you found it.
And now you're going
to give it to the First Order.
The First Order rose from the dark side.
You did not.
I'll show you the dark side.
You may try.
But you cannot deny
the truth that is your family.
You're so right.
So, who talks first?
You talk first? I talk first?
The old man gave it to you.
It's just very hard to
understand you with all the...
- Search him.
-...apparatus.
- Nothing, sir.
- Put him on board.
PHASMA". Sir, the villagers?
- Kill them all.
On my command.
Fire.
Please, no!
Nothing here.
Go ahead!
All right.
All right!
PHASMA'. FN-2187.
Submit your blaster for inspection.
Yes, Captain.
And who gave you permission
to remove that helmet?
I'm sorry, Captain.
Report to my division at once.
What you brought
me today is worth...
hmm...
one quarter portion.
Shh.
That's just Teedo. Wants you for parts.
He has no respect for anyone.
Your antenna's bent.
Where do you come from?
Classified, really?
Me too. Big secret.
Niima Outpost is that way.
Stay off Kelvin Ridge.
Keep away from
the Sinking Fields in the north.
You'll drown in the sand.
Don't follow me. Town is that way.
No!
In the morning, you go.
You're welcome.
I had no idea we had...
the best pilot in
the Resistance on board.
Comfortable?
Not really.
I'm impressed.
No one has been able to
get out of you...
what you did with the map.
You might want to rethink
your technique.
POE GRUNTS)
- Where is it?
The Resistance...
will not be intimidated by you.
Where... is it?
It's in a droid. A BB unit.
Well, then, if it's on Jakku,
we'll soon have it.
I leave that to you.
Don't give up hope.
He still might show up.
Whoever it is you're waiting for.
Classified.
I know all about waiting.
For my family.
They'll be back. One day.
Come on.
These five pieces are worth...
Let me see here... hmm...
one half portion.
Last week they were a half portion each.
What about the droid?
What about him?
I'll pay for him.
Sixty portions.
Actually...
The droid's not for sale.
Come on.
Follow the girl and get that droid.
Ren wants the prisoner.
FN-2187". Turn here.
Listen carefully.
If you do exactly as I say,
I can get you out of here.
What?
This is a rescue. I'm helping you escape.
Can you fly a TIE fighter?
You're with the Resistance?
What? No, no, no. I'm breaking you out.
- Can you fly a TIE fighter?
- I can fly anything.
Why? Why are you helping me?
Because it's the right thing to do.
You need a pilot.
I need a pilot.
We're gonna do this.
Yeah?
Okay. Stay calm. Stay calm.
- I am calm.
- I'm talking to myself.
Not yet.
Okay, go. This way.
I've always wanted to fly
one of these things.
- Can you shoot?
- Blasters, I can.
Okay, same principle.
Use the toggle on the left...
to switch between missiles,
cannons and mag pulse.
Use the sight on the right to aim.
- Triggers to fire.
- This is very complicated.
I can fix this.
We have an unsanctioned
departure from bay two.
Alert General Hux. And stop that fighter.
Fourteen failed. Eighteen...
I got it.
This thing really moves.
We gotta take out as many of
these cannons as we can...
or we're not gonna get very far.
- All right.
- I'm gonna get us in position.
Just stay sharp.
Up ahead! Up ahead! You see it?
I got us dead center.
-It's a clean shot.
- Okay, got it.
- Yeah!
- Yes!
Did you see that?
- Did you see that?
- I saw it!
Hey, what's your name?
FN-2187.
F... What?
That's the only name they ever gave me.
Well, I ain't using it. F-N, huh?
Finn. I'm gonna call you Finn.
- Is that all right?
- Finn.
Yeah. Finn, I like that.
- I like that.
- I'm Poe. Poe Dameron.
- Good to meet you, Poe.
- Good to meet you too, Finn.
Sir, they've
taken out our turbolasers.
Use the ventral cannons.
Yes, sir. Bringing them online.
KYLO REN". General Hux,
is it the Resistance pilot?
Yes, and he had help...
from one of our own.
We're checking the registers now...
to identify which stormtrooper it was.
The one from the village. FN-2187.
Sir, ventral cannons hot.
Fire.
One's coming toward you!
My right. Your left.
- Do you see it?
- Hold on.
I see him!
Nice shot!
Where are we going?
We're going back to Jakku.
That's where.
No. We can't go back to Jakku.
We need to get out of this system.
I gotta get my droid
before the First Order does.
- What, a droid?
- That's right.
He's a BB unit, orange and
white. One of a kind.
I don't care what color he is!
No droid can be that important.
This one is, pal!
We gotta get as far away from
the First Order as we can.
We go back to Jakku, we die.
That droid has a map
that leads straight to Luke Skywalker.
Oh, you gotta be kidding me!
FN-2187 reported
to my division...
was evaluated,
and sent to reconditioning.
No prior signs of nonconformity?
This was his first offense.
General!
- They've been hit.
- Destroyed?
Disabled.
They were headed back to Jakku.
The fighter is projected to
crash in the Goazon badlands.
They were going back for the droid.
Send a squad to the wreckage.
Poe!
POeI
Poe! I got you.
Supreme Leader Snoke
was explicit.
Capture the droid if we can,
but destroy it if we must.
KYLO REN". How capable
are your soldiers, General?
I won't have you question my methods.
They're obviously skilled
at committing high treason.
Perhaps Leader Snoke should
consider using a clone army.
My men are exceptionally trained.
Programmed from birth.
Then they should have
no problem retrieving the droid.
Unharmed.
Careful, Ren, that your
personal interests...
not interfere with orders
from Leader Snoke.
I want that map.
For your sake...
I suggest you get it.
Water. Water.
No water.
Water.
ls there water?
What? Oi, get off him!
Hey!
They work for Unkar.
That guy that wanted you.
He must have really wanted you.
REYI Who?
Him?
- What's your hurry, thief?
- What? Thief?
- Ow!
- Hey, what?
- The jacket.
This droid says you stole it.
I've had a pretty messed up
day, all right?
So I'd appreciate it...
if you stop accusing me of...
- Ow! Stop it!
- Where'd you get it?
It belongs to his master.
It belonged to Poe Dameron.
That was his name, right?
He was captured by the First Order.
I helped him escape,
but our ship crashed.
Poe didn't make it.
I tried to help him. I'm sorry.
So you're with the Resistance?
Obviously.
Yes, I am.
I'm with the Resistance, yeah.
I am with the Resistance.
I've never met
a Resistance fighter before.
Well, this is what we look like.
Some of us. Others look different.
BB-8 says he's on a secret mission.
He has to get back to your base.
Apparently, he has a map that
leads to Luke Skywalker...
and everyone's after it.
Luke Skywalker?
I thought he was a myth.
What?
- What are you doing?
- Come on.
Come on, BB-8!
- Let go of me!
- Come on, we gotta move!
I know how to run
without you holding my hand!
BB-8, stay close!
This way.
Call in the air strike.
Come on!
They're shooting at both of us.
Yeah. They saw you with me.
You're marked.
- Well, thanks for that.
- Hey!
I'm not the one who chased
you down with a stick.
Does anyone have
blasters around here?
Are you okay?
Stop taking my hand!
Hey-
Are you okay?
Yeah.
Follow me.
- We can't outrun them!
- We might...
in that quadjumper!
Hey, we need a pilot!
We've got one.
You?
Uh, what about that ship?
That one's garbage!
The garbage will do.
Gunner position is down there!
You ever fly this thing?
No! This ship hasn't flown in years.
Great.
Whoa.
I can do this. I can do this.
Hey!
That's mine!
Wait, stay low! Hey, stay low!
- What?
- Stay low!
It confuses their tracking.
BB-8, hold on!
I'm going low!
What are you doing back there?
Are you ever gonna fire back?
I'm working on it! Are the shields up?
Not so easy without a co-pilot!
Try sitting in this thing.
We need cover, quick!
We're about to get some!
I hope.
Damn it!
Come on, come on!
- Nice shot!
- I'm getting pretty good at this.
Uh, the cannon's stuck
in forward position.
I can't move it. You gotta lose him!
- Get ready!
- Okay. For what?
Are we really doing this?
Oh, no.
Whoo!
- Nice shooting.
- Now that was some flying.
- Thanks.
- How did you do that?
- I don't know.
- No one trained you?
I've flown some ships, but
I've never left the planet.
- Your last shot was dead-on.
- That was amazing.
- You got him with one blast!
- You set me up for it.
- It was perfect.
- That was pretty good.
You're okay. He's with the Resistance.
He's gonna get you home.
We both will.
I don't know your name.
Finn. What's yours?
I'm Rey.
Rey...
Help me with this. Quick!
Whoa, what's going on?
Sir...
we were unable to acquire
the droid on Jakku.
It escaped capture...
aboard a stolen
Corellian YT model freighter.
The droid...
stole a freighter?
Not exactly, sir.
It had help.
We have no confirmation...
but we believe FN-2187 may
have helped in the escape.
Anything else?
The two were accompanied by a girl.
What girl?
It's the motivator.
Grab me a Harris wrench,
check in there.
How bad is it?
If we wanna live, not good.
They're hunting for us now.
We've gotta get out of this system!
BB-8 said the location
of the Resistance base...
is "need to know".
If I'm taking you there, I need to know!
This?
You gotta tell us
where your base is.
I don't speak that.
All right, between us...
I'm not with the Resistance, okay?
I'm just trying to get away
from the First Order.
But you tell us where the base is...
I'll get you there first. Deal?
- Droid, please!
- Pilex driver, hurry.
- So, where's your base?
- Go on, BB-8, tell her.
Please.
- The lleenium system?
- Yeah, the lleenium system.
That's the one. Get us there
as fast as you can.
I'll drop you two at Ponemah Terminal.
I need the bonding tape, hurry!
What about you?
I gotta get back to Jakku.
Back to Jak...
Why does everyone
wanna go back to Jakku?
-It's not that one. No. No.
- That place is...
The one I'm pointing to. No.
No. No!
If we don't patch it up...
the propulsion tank will overflow...
and flood the ship with poisonous gas!
- This?
- Yes.
Hey, Rey, you're a pilot.
You can fly anywhere. Why go back?
You got a family?
You got a boyfriend? A cute boyfriend?
None of your business, that's why.
- That can't be good.
- No, it can't be.
Someone's locked on to us.
All controls are overridden.
Get off! Get off!
See anything?
Oh, no.
It's the First Order.
What do we do?
There must be something.
- You said poisonous gas.
- I fixed that.
Can you unfix it?
Come on, BB-8.
I got him.
I'm okay.
BB-8, get off me!
Do you think this will work
on the stormtroopers?
Yeah. Their masks filter out
smoke, not toxins.
- Hurry.
- I'm hurrying.
Chewie...
we're home.
Where are the others?
- Where's the pilot?
- I'm the pilot.
You?
No, it's true.
We're the only ones on board.
You can understand that thing?
And "that thing"
can understand you, too...
so watch it.
Come on out of there.
- Where'd you get this ship?
- Niima Outpost.
Jakku? Thatjunkyard?
Thank you! Junkyard.
Told you we should have
double-checked the Western Reaches.
Who had it? Ducain?
I stole it. From Unkar Plutt.
He stole it from the Irving Boys,
who stole it from Ducain.
Who stole it from me!
Well, you tell him that Han Solo...
just stole back the
Millennium Falcon for good.
This is the Millennium Falcon?
You're Han Solo?
I used to be.
Han Solo, the Rebellion general?
No, the smuggler.
Wasn't he a war hero?
This is the ship that made
the Kessel Run in 14 parsecs?
Twelve!
Fourteen.
Hey!
Some moof-milker
put a compressor on the ignition line.
Unkar Plutt did.
I thought it was a mistake,
too. Puts too much...
...stress on the hyperdrive.
Chewie, throw them in a pod.
We'll drop them at the
nearest inhabited planet.
Wait, no.
- We need your help.
- My help?
This droid has to get
to the Resistance base...
as soon as possible.
He's carrying a map to Luke Skywalker.
You are the Han Solo that
fought with the Rebellion.
You knew him.
Yeah. I knew him.
I knew Luke.
Don't tell me a Rathtar's gotten loose.
Wait, what?
Did you just say Rathtars?
Hey!
You're not hauling Rathtars
on this freighter, are you?
I'm hauling Rathtars.
Oh, great. It's the Guavian Death Gang.
Must have tracked us from Nantoon.
What's a Rathtar?
They're big and they're dangerous.
You ever heard of the Trillia Massacre?
- No.
- Good.
I got three of them going to King Prana.
Three? How'd you get them on board?
I used to have a bigger crew.
Get below and stay there
until I say so...
and don't even think about
taking the Falcon.
What about BB-8?
He stays with me
until I get rid of the gang...
then you can have him back
and be on your way.
What about the Rathtars?
Where are you keeping them?
- There's one.
- What are you gonna do?
Same thing I always do.
Talk my way out of it.
Yes, I do. Every time.
Han Solo.
You're a dead man.
Bala-Tik. What's the problem?
The problem is we loaned you
50,000 for this job.
- Can you see them?
- No.
I heard you also borrowed
50,000 from Kanjiklub.
You know you can't trust
those little freaks.
How long we known each other?
They have blasters.
A lot of them.
Not long.
We want our money back now.
You think hunting
Rathtars is cheap?
I spent that money.
Kanjiklub wants
their investment back, too.
I never made a deal with Kanjiklub!
BALA-TIKZ Tell that t0 Kanjiklub.
Tasu Leech.
Good to see you.
Boys, you're both gonna
get what I promised.
Have I ever not delivered...
-for you before?
- Yeah.
- What was the second time?
- Your game is old.
There's no one in the galaxy
left for you to swindle.
That BB unit.
The First Order is looking
for one just like it.
And two fugitives.
First I've heard of it.
Wait, wait, wait.
If we close the blast doors
in that corridor...
we can trap both gangs!
We'll close the blast doors from here?
Resetting the fuses should do it.
I got a bad feeling about this.
- Oh, no.
-"Oh, no," what?
Wrong fuses.
Kill them!
- Whoa...
- And take the droid!
- This was a mistake!
- Huge!
What do they look like?
They look like that.
- This way.
- Are you sure?
No,no,no!
Finn!
Rey!
Get Off! Get Off!
- Rey!
- Finn!
Finn!
Get off me!
FIN NI Rey!
Get off! Get off!
Finn!
- It had me! But the door...
- That was lucky.
I got the door. Cover us!
Chewie!
You okay?
Wow.
Come on! Come on!
Han.
You, close the door behind us.
You, take care of Chewie!
Hey, where are you going?
Unkar Plutt installed a fuel pump, too.
If we don't prime that,
we're not going anywhere.
I hate that guy.
- And you could use a co-pilot.
- I got one, he's back there.
Watch the thrust. We're going
out of here at lightspeed.
From inside the hangar?
Is that even possible?
I never ask that question
till after I've done it.
RAT HT AR GROW LS)
{REY YELP S';
This is not how I thought
this day was gonna go.
Angle the shield. Hang on back there.
No problem!
Come on, baby, don't let me down.
- What?
- Compressor.
Inform the First Order...
that Han Solo has the droid they want.
And it's aboard the Millennium Falcon.
The droid will soon be
delivered to the Resistance...
leading them to the last Jedi.
If Skywalker returns...
the new Jedi will rise.
Supreme Leader,
I take full responsibility...
General!
Our strategy must now change.
The weapon. It is ready.
I believe the time has come to use it.
We shall destroy the government...
that supports the Resistance...
the Republic.
Without their friends to protect them...
the Resistance will be vulnerable.
And we will stop them
before they reach Skywalker.
Go.
Oversee preparations.
Yes, Supreme Leader.
There has been an awakening.
Have you felt it?
Yes.
There's something more.
The droid we seek is aboard
the Millennium Falcon.
In the hands of your father...
Han Solo.
He means nothing to me.
Even you, master of the
Knights of Ren...
have never faced such a test.
By the grace of your training,
I will not be seduced.
We shall see.
- Electrical overload.
- I can fix that.
Coolant's leaking.
Try transferring auxiliary power...
...to the secondary tank.
I got it.
Chewie, come on!
I need help with this giant hairy thing!
Stop moving!
FINNI Chewie!
You hurt Chewie,
you're gonna deal with me!
Hurt him? He almost killed me six times!
Which is fine!
This hyperdrive blows,
there are gonna be...
pieces of us in three different systems.
What'd you do?
I bypassed the compressor.
Huh.
Move, ball.
Ah, don't say that.
You did great. Just rest.
Good job, kid.
Thanks.
You're welcome.
HAN; So...
fugitives, huh?
The First Order wants the map.
Finn is with the Resistance.
I'm just a scavenger.
Let's see what you got.
Go ahead.
This map's not complete.
It's just a piece.
Ever since Luke disappeared...
people have been looking for him.
Why did he leave?
He was training
a new generation of Jedi.
One boy, an apprentice...
turned against him, destroyed it all.
Luke felt responsible.
He just walked away from everything.
Do you know what happened to him?
A lot of rumors. Stories.
People that knew him best...
think he went looking
for the first Jedi temple.
The Jedi were real?
I used to wonder about that myself.
Thought it was a bunch
of mumbo-jumbo.
A magical power holding
together good and evil...
the dark side and the light.
Crazy thing is...
it's true.
The Force. The Jedi.
All Of it.
It's all true.
No, you rest.
You want my help? You're getting it.
Gonna see an old friend.
She'll get your droid home.
This is our stop.
I didn't know there was
this much green...
in the whole galaxy.
Hey, Solo, I'm not sure what
we're walking into here...
Did you just call me Solo?
Sorry. Han. Mr. Solo.
You should know...
I'm a big deal in the Resistance.
Which puts a real target on my back.
Are there any conspirators here?
Like, First Order sympathizers?
Listen, Big Deal.
You got another problem.
Women always figure out the truth.
Always.
You might need this.
I think I can handle myself.
I know you do. That's why
I'm giving it to you.
Take it.
You know how to use one of those?
Yeah. You pull the trigger.
Little bit more to it than that.
You got a lot to learn.
You got a name?
REY -
I been thinking about bringing
on some more crew, Rey.
A second mate. Someone to help out.
Someone who can keep up
with Chewie and me...
appreciates the Falcon.
Are you offering me a job?
I wouldn't be nice to you.
Doesn't pay much.
You're offering me a job.
I'm thinking about it.
Well?
If you were, I'd be flattered.
But I have to get home.
Where, Jakku?
I've already been away too long.
Chewie, check out the ship
as best you can.
That's too bad. Chewie kind of likes you.
Solo, why are we here again?
To get your droid on a clean ship.
Clean?
You think it was luck
that Chewie and I found the Falcon?
If we can find it on our scanners...
the First Order's not far behind.
Wanna get BB-8 to the Resistance?
Maz Kanata's our best bet.
We can trust her, right?
Relax, kid.
She's run this watering hole
for a thousand years.
Maz is a bit of an acquired taste...
so let me do the talking.
And whatever you do, don't stare.
At what?
Any of it.
Han Solo!
Oh, boy.
Hey, Maz.
Where's my boyfriend?
Chewie's working on the Falcon.
I like that Wookiee.
I assume you need something.
Desperately.
Let's get to it.
KYLO REN". Forgive me.
I feel it again.
The pull to the light.
Supreme Leader senses it.
Show me again.
The power of the darkness.
And I will let nothing stand in our way.
Show me...
Grandfather...
and I Will finish...
what you started.
A map.
To Skywalker himself?
You are right back
in the mess.
Maz, I need you to get this droid to Leia.
Hmm...
No.
You've been running away
from this fight for too long.
Han.
Go home.
Leia doesn't wanna see me.
Please, we came here for your help.
What fight?
The only fight.
Against the dark side.
Through the ages...
I've seen evil take many forms.
The Sith. The Empire.
Today, it is the First Order.
Their shadow is spreading
across the galaxy.
We must face them.
Fight them.
All of us.
There is no fight against the First Order.
Not one we can win.
Look around.
There's no chance we haven't
been recognized already.
I bet you the First Order
is on their way right...
What's this?
What are you doing?
Solo, what is she doing?
I don't know. But it ain't good.
If you live long enough...
you see the same eyes
in different people.
I'm looking at the eyes
of a man who wants to run.
You don't know a thing about me.
Where I'm from. What I've seen.
You don't know the First Order like I do.
They'll slaughter us.
We all need to run.
Hmm.
You see those two?
They'll trade work for transportation...
to the Outer Rim.
There, you can disappear.
Finn?
Come with me.
What about BB-8? We're not done yet.
We have to get him back to your base.
I can't.
Keep it, kid.
Who's the girl?
I was told you can get me
to the Outer Rim.
What are you doing?
Don't leave without me.
You can't just go. I won't let you.
I'm not who you think I am.
Finn, what are you talking about?
I'm not Resistance.
I'm not a hero.
I'm a stormtrooper.
Like all of them, I was taken
from a family I'll never know.
And raised to do one thing.
But my first battle, I made a choice.
I wasn't gonna kill for them.
So I ran. Right into you.
And you looked at me
like no one ever had.
I was ashamed of what I was.
But I'm done with the First Order.
I'm never going back.
Rey, come with me.
Don't go.
Take care of yourself.
Please.
No!
No! Come back!
Come back!
No!
Its energy...
- ...surrounds us...
- No!
...and binds us...
The Force will be...
No!
Come back!
UNKAR". Quiet, girl.
No!
Rey?
These are your first steps.
What was that?
I shouldn't have gone in there.
That lightsaber was Luke's.
And his father's before him.
And now, it calls to you.
I have to get back to Jakku.
Han told me.
Dear child.
I see your eyes.
You already know the truth.
Whomever you're waiting for on Jakku...
they're never coming back.
But...
there's someone who still could.
Luke.
The belonging you seek
is not behind you...
it is ahead.
I am no Jedi, but I know the Force.
It moves through and surrounds
every living thing.
Close your eyes.
Feel it.
The light...
it's always been there.
It will guide you.
The saber. Take it.
I'm never touching that thing again.
I don't want any part of this.
Hmm.
Today is the end
of the Republic.
The end of a regime
that acquiesces to disorder.
At this very moment,
in a system far from here...
the New Republic lies to the galaxy...
while secretly supporting
the treachery...
of the loathsome Resistance.
This fierce machine
which you have built...
upon which we stand...
will bring an end to the Senate!
To their cherished fleet!
All remaining systems
will bow to the First Order!
And will remember this...
as the last day of the Republic!
Confirm transfer to manual control.
Configure!
Fire!
CITIZEN; No. What is it?
It was the Republic.
The First Order, they've done it.
Where's Rey?
What are you doing?
You have to go back.
I'm leaving.
BB-8...
No, you can't.
You have to go back,
you're too important.
They'll help you.
I've had this for ages.
Kept it locked away.
Where'd you get that?
A good question. For another time.
Take it.
Find your friend!
Those beasts.
They're here.
FN-417, hold position.
Oh, safety.
STORMTROOPERI Sir.
The droid was spotted heading west.
With a girl.
You have to keep going.
Stay out of sight.
I'll try to fight them off.
I hope so, too.
Come on, Chewie!
Rey and BB-8! They need you!
Now! Go!
I need a weapon!
You have one!
Hey, can I try that?
I like this thing.
Traitor!
- You okay, Big Deal?
- Thanks.
Don't move-.
TK-338, we have targets in custody.
We have incoming at 28. 6.
Move! Move! Move!
Scramble all squads, repeat,
scramble all squads!
Head to higher cover and wait
for our position!
It's the Resistance.
Go straight at them!
Don't let these dogs scare you!
- JESS". Copy that.
- We're with you, Poe.
Quick!
Whoo! Yeah!
That's one hell of a pilot!
Whoo-hoo!
mam SABER HUMS)
The girl I've heard so much about.
The droid.
Where is it?
Request air support.
The map.
You've seen it.
Sir, Resistance fighters.
We need more troops.
KYLO REN'. Pull the division out.
Forget the droid.
We have what we need.
Pull back to tree line!
No!
No, no!
No! No!
Rey!
He took her. Did you see that?
He took her. She's gone.
Yeah, I know.
Let's g0.
Goodness! Han Solo!
It is I, C-3PO.
You probably don't recognize me...
because of the red arm.
Look who it is, did you see who...
Uh...
Hmm.
Excuse me, Prin... General. Sorry.
Come along, BB-8, quickly.
Yes, I must get
my proper arm reinstalled.
You changed your hair.
Same jacket.
No, new jacket.
I saw him.
Leia, I saw our son.
He was here.
CREWMANI Hey!
BB-8, my buddy.
Oh, it's so good to see you.
Finn saved you?
Where is he?
Poe?
Oh, n0.
Poe Dameron, you're alive?
- Buddy! So are you!
- What happened to you?
I got thrown from the crash.
I woke up at night.
No you. No ship. Nothing.
BB-8 says that you saved him.
No, no, no. It wasn'tjust me.
You completed my mission, Finn...
That's my jacket.
- Oh...
- No, no, no.
Keep it. It suits you.
You're a good man, Finn.
Poe, I need your help.
PZ-4CO,
report to communications.
General Organa...
I'm sorry to interrupt. This is Finn.
- He needs to talk to you.
- And I need to talk to him.
That was incredibly brave what you did.
Renouncing the First Order,
saving this man's life.
Thank you, ma'am. But a friend
of mine was taken prisoner.
Han told me about the girl.
I'm sorry.
Finn's familiar with the weapon
that destroyed the Hosnian system.
He worked on the base.
We're desperate for anything
you can tell us.
That's where my friend was taken.
I've got to get there fast.
And I will do everything I can to help...
but first you need to tell us
all you know.
That sounds very scary.
You must be so brave.
General...
I regret to inform you...
but this map recovered from BB-8...
is only partially complete.
And even worse, it matches
no charted system on record.
We simply do not have
enough information...
to locate Master Luke.
Can't believe I was so foolish
to think I could find Luke...
and bring him home.
Leia.
Don't do that.
Do what?
Anything-
Princesses.
I'm trying to be helpful.
When did that ever help?
And don't say the Death Star.
C-3POI BB-8.
You're wasting your time.
It is very doubtful that R2 would have
the rest of the map in his backup data.
I am afraid not.
R2-D2 has been in low-power mode
ever since Master Luke went away.
Sadly, he may never be
his old self again.
Listen to me, will you?
I know every time you...
Every time you look at me
you're reminded of him.
You think I want to forget him?
I want him back.
There's nothing more we could
have done.
There's too much Vader in him.
That's why I wanted him
to train with Luke.
I just never should have sent him away.
That's when I lost him.
That's when I lost you both.
We both had to deal with it
in our own way.
I went back to the only thing
I was ever any good at.
We both did.
We lost our son.
Forever.
No.
It was Snoke.
He seduced our son to the dark side.
But we can still save him.
Me.
You.
If Luke couldn't reach him, how could I?
Luke is a Jedi.
You're his father.
There is still light in him, I know it.
General...
the reconnaissance report
on the enemy base is coming.
Where am I?
You're my guest.
Where are the others?
Do you mean the murderers...
traitors, and thieves you call friends?
You'll be relieved to hear
I have no idea.
You still want to kill me.
That happens
when you're being hunted...
by a creature in a mask.
Tell me about the droid.
He's a BB unit with a selenium drive...
and a thermal hyperscan vindicator.
It's carrying a section
of a navigational chart.
And we have the rest.
Recovered from the archives
of the Empire...
but we need the last piece.
And somehow you convinced
the droid to show it to you.
You.
A scavenger.
You know I can take whatever I want.
You're so lonely.
So afraid to leave.
At night, desperate to sleep.
You imagine an ocean.
I see it.
I see the island.
And Han Solo.
You feel like he's the father
you never had.
He would have disappointed you.
Get out of my head.
I know you've seen the map.
It's in there.
And now you'll give it to me.
Don't be afraid. I feel it, too.
I'm not giving you anything.
We'll see.
You.
You're afraid.
That you will never be
as strong as Darth Vader.
The scavenger...
resisted you?
She is strong with the Force.
Untrained, but stronger than she knows.
And the droid?
Ren believed it was no longer
valuable to us.
That the girl was all we needed.
As a result, the droid has
most likely been returned...
to the hands of the enemy.
They may have the map already.
Then the Resistance
must be destroyed...
before they get to Skywalker.
We have their location.
We tracked their reconnaissance ship
to the lleenium system.
Good.
Then we will crush them
once and for all.
Prepare the weapon.
Supreme Leader, I can get
the map from the girl.
I just need your guidance.
If what you say about this girl is true...
Bring her to me.
You will remove these restraints...
and leave this cell with the door open.
STORMTROOPER". What did you say?
You will remove these restraints...
and leave this cell with the door open.
I'll tighten
those restraints...
SCHVGHQGF scum.
You will remove these restraints...
and leave this cell with the door open.
I will remove
these restraints...
and leave the cell with the door open.
- And you'll drop your weapon.
- And I'll drop my weapon.
No.
Guards!
Begin charging the weapon.
Yes, sir.
Weapon charging.
The scan data from Snap's
reconnaissance flight...
confirms Finn's report.
They've somehow created
a hyper-lightspeed weapon...
built within the planet itself.
A laser cannon?
We're not sure how to describe
a weapon of this scale.
It's another Death Star.
I wish that were the case, Major.
This was the Death Star.
And this is Starkiller Base.
So, it's big.
How is it possible to power
a weapon of that size?
It uses the power of the sun.
As the weapon is charged...
the sun is drained until it disappears.
Ma'am.
The First Order...
they're charging the weapon again now.
Our system is the next target.
Oh, my.
Without the Republic fleet,
we're doomed.
Okay. How do we blow it up?
- There's always a way to do that.
- Han's right.
In order
for that amount of power...
to be contained...
that base has to have some
kind of thermal oscillator.
There is one. Precinct 47.
Here.
If we can destroy
that oscillator...
it might destabilize the core
and cripple the weapon.
- Maybe the planet.
- We'll go in there,
we'll hit that oscillator
with everything we've got.
They have defensive shields...
that our ships cannot penetrate.
We disable the shields.
Kid, you worked there.
What do you got?
I can do it.
I like this guy.
I can disable the shields,
but I have to be there.
On the planet.
- We'll get you there.
- Han, how?
If I told you, you wouldn't like it.
So we disable the shields...
we take out the oscillator
and we blow up their big gun.
All right. Let's go.
Chewie, check that donal capitator.
Come on. Let's go.
Finn, be careful with those.
They're explosives.
Now you tell me?
You know, no matter
how much we fought...
I've always hated watching you leave.
That's why I did it.
So you'd miss me.
I did miss you.
It wasn't all bad, was it?
Huh?
Some of it was... good.
Pretty good.
- Some things never change.
- True.
You still drive me crazy.
If you see our son...
bring him home.
Sir, sensors
triggered in Hangar 718.
We're searching the area.
She's just beginning
to test her powers.
The longer it takes to find her...
the more dangerous she becomes.
All sentry droids...
all sentry droids...
resynchronize
to Galactic Standard Time.
Offset 473.
How are we getting in?
Their shields have
a fractional refresh rate.
Keeps anything traveling
slower than lightspeed...
from getting through.
We're making our landing
approach at lightspeed?
Chewie, get ready.
And... Now!
I am pulling up!
I get any higher...
they'll see us!
Sir, she was
not found in Hangar 718.
But all troops are on alert.
Put every hangar on lockdown.
She's going to try to steal
a ship to esc...
Han Solo.
The flooding tunnel is over that ridge.
We'll get in that way.
What was your job
when you were based here?
Sanitation.
Sanitation?
Then how do you know
how to disable the shields?
I don't.
I'm just here to get Rey.
People are counting on us.
The galaxy is counting on us.
Solo, we'll figure it out.
We'll use the Force.
That's not how the Force works.
Oh, really? You're cold?
Come on.
Report.
Weapon charged in 15 minutes, sir.
Hey!
The longer we're here
the less luck we're gonna have.
- The shields.
- I have an idea about that.
- You remember me?
- FN-2187.
Not anymore.
The name's Finn and I'm in charge.
I'm in charge now, Phasma.
I'm in charge.
- Bring it down. Bring it down.
- Yeah.
Follow me.
Have you
checked out the new T-17s?
The T-17s,
as far as I can tell...
are a great improvement.
STORMTROOPER 1". Yeah.
That's what they tell you.
But believe me, they don't hold up.
- They don't?
- No.
You want me to blast
that bucket off your head?
Lower the shields.
You're making a big mistake.
Do it.
Solo, if this works...
we're not gonna have
a lot of time to find Rey.
Don't worry, kid.
We won't leave here without her.
You can't be so stupid
as to think this will be easy.
My troops will storm
this block and kill you all.
I disagree. What do we do with her?
Is there a garbage chute?
Trash compactor?
Yeah, there is.
General, their shields are down.
Thank the Maker!
Han did it. Send them in.
Give Poe full authorization for attack.
Black Leader,
go to sub-lights on your call.
Roger, base.
Red squad, Blue squad, take my lead.
Dropping out of lightspeed.
Almost in range.
Hit the target dead center.
As many runs as we can get.
Approaching target.
Fighters incoming!
OFFICER 2; Coming at 28.336.
Forty-five!
Shields up! Shields up!
Dispatch all squadrons.
Yes, General.
All right. Let's light it up.
- Ah, direct hit.
- But no damage!
Yeah, we gotta
keep hitting it.
Another bombing run.
Remember, when the sun is gone
that weapon will be ready to fire.
But as long as there's light,
we got a chance.
Guys, we got a lot of company!
We think
they may be splitting up.
Heading to quadrants 4 and 5.
We'll use the charges
to blow that blast door.
I'll go in and draw fire,
but I'm gonna need cover.
You sure you're up for this?
Hell, no.
I'll go in and try to find Rey.
The troopers will be on our tail.
We have to be ready for that.
There's an access tunnel that leads...
Why are you doing that? Hmm?
Why are you doing this?
I'm trying to come up with a plan.
You all right?
- Yeah.
- Good.
What happened to you?
Did he hurt you?
Finn, what are you doing here?
We came back for you.
What'd he say?
That it was your idea.
Thank you.
How did you get away?
I can't explain it.
And you wouldn't believe it.
Escape now, hug later.
I got one behind me.
- You see it?
- Yeah. I'm on it.
- Burillo's been hit.
- Watch out for ground fire.
They're in trouble.
We can't leave.
My friend's got a bag full of explosives.
Let's use them.
General, are you seeing this?
Two more X-wings down.
That's half our fleet destroyed.
And their weapon
will be fully charged in ten minutes.
It would take a miracle to save us now.
Ah.
Girl knows her stuff.
We'll set the charges
against every other column.
You're right. That's a better idea.
You take the top. I'll go down below.
Detonator.
We'll meet back here.
Find them.
Ben!
Han Solo.
I've been waiting for this day
for a long time.
Take off that mask. You don't need it.
What do you think you'll see if I do?
The face of my son.
Your son is gone.
He was weak and foolish like his father.
So I destroyed him.
That's what Snoke wants you to believe.
But it's not true.
My son is alive.
No.
The Supreme Leader is wise.
Snoke is using you for your power.
When he gets what he wants,
he'll crush you.
You know it's true.
It's too late.
No, it's not.
Leave here with me. Come home.
We miss you.
I'm being torn apart.
I want to be free of this pain.
I know what I have to do...
but I don't know if I have
the strength to do it.
Will you help me?
Yes. Anything.
REYI No!
Thank you.
No.
The oscillator's been damaged...
but is still functional.
Admiral, their weapon
will fire in two minutes.
The Falcon's this way.
We're not done yet.
You're a monster.
It's just us now.
Han Solo can't save you.
Rey!
REY -
Oh, no. No, no.
Traitor!
That lightsaber.
It belongs to me.
Come get it.
We just lost R-1.
We're overwhelmed.
What do we do? It isn't working.
Black Leader, there's a brand
new hole in that oscillator.
Looks like our friends got in.
Red Four, Red Six, cover us.
- I'm on it.
- Roger.
Everybody else, hit the target hard.
Give it everything you got.
I need some help here.
I need some help!
- Coming in!
- Watch out!
I'm hit!
All teams, I'm going in.
Pull up and cover me.
Copy that, Black Leader.
Good luck, Poe.
Weapon fully charged in 30 seconds.
Prepare to fire.
You need a teacher.
I could show you the ways of the Force.
The Force?
All eyes on that TIE fighter.
We're losing power rapidly!
Lieutenant!
Get back to your station!
Just look! We won't survive.
Even Hux is gone.
Supreme Leader.
The fuel cells have ruptured.
The collapse of the planet has begun.
Leave the base at once
and come to me with Kylo Ren.
It is time...
to complete his training.
Finn!
Finn.
- All teams, I got eyes on them.
- Yes!
Our job's done here. Let's go home.
Easy, easy. He's hurt.
We've got a heartbeat.
C-3POI R2-D2!
You've come back.
You found what?
How dare you call me that!
Find Master Luke, how?
Come, R2.
We must go tell the others at once!
General.
Excuse me, General.
R2 may contain some
much-needed good news.
Tell me.
Yeah. All right, buddy. Hold on.
The map, it is complete.
Luke.
Oh, my dear friend...
how I've missed you.
We'll see each other again.
I believe that.
Thank you, my friend.
Rey.
May the Force be with you.